Guide to the Yale Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Numerical, Series II
  - No. 172: Holden, Daniel Judson (1844-1903): 110 ALS chiefly written to his sister, Katherine J. Holden while Daniel J. Holden was a student at Yale College. In addition to accounts of his studies and student life, there are references to the Civil War, among them a draft among students at Yale College in 1863 and expected riots in New Haven. There is also an account of a walking tour from New Haven to Boston in 1964. With a typewritten transcript, prefaced by an explanatory note (1957) by the writer's daughter, Edith Holden. Her father's picture, copied from the Yale Class Album of 1864, is also included, 1859 August 29-1864 August 28, 1957 (Box 56)
  - No. 173: Carroll, Douglas Gordon (1915-1977): TMS (copy), diaries 1929-1947, including those for his years at Yale College, 1933-1938 (Box 57)
  - No. 174: Hayman, Ike, of Rutherford, N.J., collector: "Yale men who served on the bench of the United States Supreme Court," a collection of portraits and autographs, written 1790-1951, comprising 13 portraits and thirteen manuscripts. (Box 58)
  - No. 175: Pelikan, Jaroslav Jan (1923-): TMS (electrostatic copy) "Yale's collections - A national treasure." An address to Assembly XX of the Association of Yale Alumni, on April 1, 1982 by Jaroslav Pelikan, Sterling Professor of History, April 1-3, 1982 (Box 59)
  - No. 176: Bridgewater, Dorothy W: TMS, "The Yale Library of 1742.", undated (Box 59)
  - No. 177: Stetson, Charles Pierce (1835-1899): Letters to Charles P. Stetson from his sister, Anna Maria, and from a friend, Franklin A. Wilson at Bowdoin College, comparing it with Yale College. Also a notice of his election to the Yale Chapter of Phi Beta Kappa in 1854, 1850-1854 (Box 59)
  - No. 178: Coe, Henry Clarke (1856-1940): ALS to "My dear Cleveland" inviting him to speak on "medical men and 'medical preparedness'" at a meeting of the M.R.C. Association, 1917 January 10 (Box 59)
  - No. 179: Sander, Anton (1851-1881): 34 ALS to his friend, O.G. Felland, with whom he had been a student at Luther College in Decorah, Iowa. Most of the letters are from Yale College (1875-1877) where Sander was studying from his Ph.D. The remaining letters (1878-1880) are from various teaching posts in Lawrenceville, New Jersey, Decorah, Iowa and Flusing, New York. Included also is an obiturary on Sander's death from a Norwegian newspaper published in Decorah, Iowa (1881 Jan 27) with an English translation, 1875 September 1-1881 January 27 (Box 59)
  - No. 180: Mallery, Garrick (1831-1894): Army officer and ethnologist. Autograph album and manuscript diary (2 copies) kept during his last two years at Yale College (1849-1850); essays on the Mormons and Chinese in California, on American Indians and an incomplete letter, probably to his father, describing a trip on a steamboat on the Missouri, 1849-188- (Box 59)
  - No. 181: Taft, Horace Dutton (1861-1943): 2 ALS to Sarah Jarvis (Brush) McLaughlin on the occasion of the death of her husband, Edward Tompkins McLaughlin, 1893 July 31, August 19 (Box 59)
  - No. 182: Pardee, Joseph Harvey (1818-1868): ALS to Romeo Lowrey while a student at Yale College on a matter of discipline, 1817 November 27 (Box 59)
  - No. 183: Seropyan, Christopher Dicran (1825-1874): ALS to Munroe & Co. in Boston ordering twelve copies of the Oration of Demosthenes on the Crown, 1851 September 15 (Box 59)
  - No. 184: Nichols, Alfred Bull (1852-1913): 42 ALS to Edward P. Noyes, mostly written while Nicholas was a tutor in German at Yale College (1884-1887) and later while traveling and studying in Germany (1888-1890). His comments from Berlin on German life and politics, particularly on the brief region of Frederick III, with a vivid portrait of the hostile public attitude toward the Empress are of particular interest. Included also are several letters by others to members of the Noyes family and a carte de visite photograph of Benjamin W. Dwight, 1884-1910 (Box 59)
  - No. 185: Thorneycroft, Thomas (1822-1903)(compiler): Scrapbook titled, "Mr. Spitzer's Visit to England, August 1899. Presented by Lieut.-Col. Thorneycroft, Tettenhall Towers." It contains photographs, manuscript essays and poetry, clippings, drawings, pamphlets and other printed matter, music and memorabilia, most of it pertaining to Thorneycroft, his family and his estate. (Box 60)
  - No. 186: Commonplace-book (ca. 1803): Transcriptions of poems, epitaphs and the texts of songs, some referring to Yale College. Included is a copy of The Yaliad by Cyrus Pearce, poems by Dr. [Timothy] Dwight and John Trumbull and songs composed in connection with a Republican meeting in New Haven (Box 61)
  - No. 187: Babcock, Thorpe (1885-1979): TMS (carbon copy), "Chuck Lambert of Yale." Enclosure: 2 ms pages by the author's sister, Corinne Babcock. A fictionalized autobiography of the author's life after graduation from Yale (Box 62)
  - No. 188: Brady, Richard J.: Stalag - Luft III, Bob Neary, 1946; scrapbook of photographs, clippings, & cables, 1942-1945 (Box 63)
    [numerical #188]
  - No. 189: Judson, Albert, (d. 1839): Yale diploma, 1821; Missionary Society broadside, 1804; and sermons, 1837, of Albert Judson, Class of 1821 (Box 63)
  - No. 190: Weeks, William Jones (1821-1897): Diary, 1849-1884, of William Jones Weeks, Glass of 1844; & ALS from his mother, 1842 Nov 27, to him at Yale College (Box 63)
  - No. 191: Chadwick, George Brewster: Letters (Box 64)
  - No. 192: Knapp, Jared (1816-1818): Letters (Box 64)
  - No. 193: McGregor, Donald Rait (1906-): Christmas Magic: song ms (photocopy) words and music, 1967 (Box 64)
    Transferred to Miscellaneous Mss Ms. Group No. 352
  - No. 194: Shay, Leo: Letter (Box 64)
  - No. 195: Dulles, Charles W.: Letters (Box 64)
  - No. 196: Hankins, John E: Yale Memories Letters (Box 64)
  - No. 197: Fitch, Jonathan: Certificate of appointment - a beadle, [1787?] (Box 64)
  - No. 198: Eddy, Maxon Hunter (1907-1983): Unpublished selected works of Max Eddy, fifteen short stories and a poem (Box 64)
  - No. 199: Smith, Maurice R.: Letters, telegram and invitation from Maurice R. Smith to Margaret E. Beckley, 1915 (Box 64)
  - No. 200: Williams, Stephen (Harvard 1713): ALS to unknown recipient on the need to have a professor of divinity at Yale College, 1753 (Box 64)
  - No. 201: Smyth, Ralph Dunning (1804-1874): Volume, "Sketches of the Graduates of Yale College 1702-1767," with correspondence, statistics on Connecticut election sermons, and miscellaneous items, undated (Box 64)
  - No. 202: Hine, Charles Daniel (1845-1923): Typescript by DeWitt C. Allen, "Charles D. Hine and His Public Service," with photographs, undated (Box 64)
  - No. 203: Eddy, Willard (1845-1932): Notarized application for Latin professorship at Knox College, Galesburg, Illinois, addressed to Newton Bateman, president of Knox College, 1883 (Box 64)
  - No. 204: Waters, William Everett (1856-1924): ALS from Edward B. Clapp to Newton Bateman, recommending Waters for the Latin professorship at Knox College, [1889?] (Box 64)
  - No. 205: Baldwin, Abraham (1754-1807): 3 first day covers issued to commemorate the 200th anniversary of the chartering of the University of Georgia, with Abraham Baldwin stamp, with related printed matter, 1985 (Box 64)
  - No. 206: Thorn, Frost (1850-1876): Yale correspondence and memorabilia, 1867-1869, undated (Box 64)
  - No. 207: Stuart, Moses (1780-1852): ALS to Joel Dawes, 1836 (Box 64)
  - No. 208: Miller, Hiram (1880-1945): Manuscript, "The Filtration of Public Water Supply by the Slow Sand Method", and field book for Mazatlan Extension, [Mexican International Railroad?], undated (Box 64)
  - No. 209: Williams, Chauncey Pratt (1860-1936): Correspondence, mostly re: Western Americana, Yale student notebook and receipts, obituary, miscellaneous papers, 1880-1937 (Box 65)
  - No. 210: Moffat, James Clement (1811-1890): ALS to John Sean McCulloch describing an abolitionist's attempt to speak at Yale College, 1836 (Box 65)
  - No. 211: Class of 1903: "Table 12": Poems by Harold T. Clark and Arthur M. Collins, 1903-1905 (Box 65)
  - No. 212: Yale Batteries at Tobyhanna, Pennsylvania: Letters to Sherman Child re: possible 50th anniversary celebration, 1965 (Box 65)
  - No. 213: Chapman, Aaron Bennett (1852-1923): Notebook with essays "Base Ball Memories," on the early history of the game in New Haven and at Yale College, "Orchestra Days," "My Theory of the Garden of Eden," and "My Idea of Heaven", 1893-1894 (Box 65)
  - No. 214: Sherman, Charles Phineas (1874-1962): ALS to his Canon Law class at Yale, 1917 (Box 65)
  - No. 215: Haldeman, Richard J. (Yale, 1851): Letters of a Pennsylvania politician and newspaper editor, 1848-1872 (Box 65)
  - No. 216: Rolfe, Robert (Yale, 1-82): Letters to brother Lawrence Rolfe (Yale, 1881), 1881-1882 (Box 65)
  - No. 217: Brace, Joab: Account book, 1810-1833 (Box 65)
  - No. 218: Ross, Richard Stellan (1918-1981, class of 1939): Correspondence written during WWII pertaining to the Battle of the Bulge, 1944 July-1945 February 11 (Box 65, Folder 218)
  - No. 219: Prann, John Richard (1917-, class of 1939): Correspondence primarily written aboard the U.S.S. Wasp, 1939-1949 (Box 65)
  - No. 220: Hall, Reginald Heber (1832-1872, class of 1852): Letter written as a student, 1850 October 24 (Box 65)
  - No. 221: Bergin, Thomas G. (Class of 1925): Postcards to Preston Beyer, 1986 May 9, July 28, 1987 August 8 (Box 65)
  - No. 222: Taylor, Nathaniel W.: ALS to Benjamin Ely, 1850 January 15 (Box 65)
  - No. 222: Hadley, James, Jr.: ALS to Daniel P. Noyes, 1848 May 13 (Box 65)
  - No. 223: Daniels, Mary Ann: ALS to Ann Spencer, 1823 November 28 (Box 65)
  - No. 224: Brown, Frank E.: Diplomas, certificates, and announcements of the former professor of Latin and master of Jonathan Edwards College, 1938-1983 (Box 65)
    See also: Series III
  - No. 225: Weiler, Theodore C.: "Sumner and Keller: Anthropological Sociologists," Humanities Lecture, University of Maine, 1963 April 14 (Box 65)
  - No. 226: Moseley, James Alexander, Jr. (Class of 1915): Correspondence and printed material pertaining to his death and memorial services, 1918-1922, 1932, 1970, undated (Box 65)
    (Materials were found in class history volume)
  - No. 227: Nathan Hale commemorative postal cards, first day of issue, and dedication program, Coventry, CT, 1977 October 14 (Box 65)
  - No. 228: Jacobson, Nathan: "A Personal History", 1989 (Box 66)
  - No. 229: Goebel, Lee: "Prayer and Polity in New England in Commemoration of the Founding of Yale College," with accompanying correspondence, 1986 (Box 66)
  - No. 230: Hincks, Edward Young (Class of 1866): Letter written as a student, 1864 October 26 (Box 66)
  - No. 231: Harwood, Forest Henry (Class of 1843, non-grad): Letter written as a student, 1839 (Box 66)
  - No. 232: "Catalogus Recentium," Yale College, 1781 (Box 66)
  - No. 233: Menner, Robert J. (Class of 1913): Postcards to his mother, 1909-1913 (Box 66)
  - No. 234: [Amory, Amey?] [Class of 1945?]: "A Play in the Greek Manner", undated (Box 66)
  - No. 235: Baur, George (assistant professor of osteology, 1885-1890): Professional correspondence with Othniel C. Marsh and others, 1887-1890 (Box 66)
  - No. 236: Brush, Samuel S. (Class of 1795): Certificate of proficiency in Latin and Greek languages from Union Hall Academy, Jamaica, Nassau, 1792 October 6 (Box 66)
  - No. 237: Chauncy, Charles (1705-1787): ALS to Ebenezer Silliman (Class of 1727) re the William Pennoyer bequest to Harvard College, 1768 October 3 (Box 66)
  - No. 238: Fisher, Alexander Metcalf (1794-1822)(Class of 1813): Mathematical memoranda, excerpt of letter describing Fisher's death at sea, memorial in Latin, 1822, undated (Box 66)
  - No. 239: Fitch, Eleazar Thompson (1791-1871) (Class of 1810): ALS to Seth Bliss re religious revival, 1831 March 21 (Box 66)
  - No. 240: Kilby, Charles (honorary M.D. degree, 1789): Personal and professional correspondence re medical degree, 1787-1788 (Box 66)
  - No. 241: Approximately 160 receipts, primarily documenting Yale business transactions with local vendors, student prizes, and student living expenses, 1865-1869 (Box 66)
  - No. 242: Giamatti, A. Bartlett (President, Yale University 1975-1986): Commemorative stamp issued at Saint Vincent, [post 1989] (Box 66)
  - No. 243: Welch, Pierce Noble (Class of 1862): Diary kept during senior year at General Russell's Institute, New Haven and freshman year at Yale College, includes biographical material, 1857 November 23-1859 May 29 (Box 66)
  - No. 244: Horowitz, William (Class of 1929): Record book kept from 1971 May-1972 January for the period served as Acting Master of Branford College, unbound pages of diary entries, 1965-1966, 1965-1966, 1971 May-1972 Jan, undated (Box 66)
  - No. 245: Hewitt, Gurdon (Class of 1847, Law School): Letter to Henry Barto describing early law curriculum and Yale social life, 1847 January 21 (Box 66)
  - No. 246: Farwell, Granger (Class of 1878, Sheffield Scientific School): Letters to his father relating his student experiences, 1875 October 4, 1876 October 15 (Box 66)
  - No. 247: Eliot, Jared (Yale Fellow, 1730-1763): Document claiming land in Killingworth, 1734 May 14 (Box 66)
  - No. 248: Nevins, William: Letter to the Reverend Professor Goodrich of Yale College on behalf of George Meredith's admission, 1827 October 22 (Box 66)
  - No. 249: Whittelsey, Samuel (Class of 1705): Letter to his brother-in-law, Nathaniel Chauncey (Class of 1702) describing accident to Elisha, Whittelsey's son, 1741/2 March 19 (Box 66)
  - No. 250: Pitkin, Timothy, Jr. (Class of.1785): "Correspondence of A Gentleman from Connecticut: His Social and Political Background in 1806," (typescript of transcribed letters), photographs, and related correspondence, biographical material, 1804-1806 (Box 66)
  - No. 251: Moore, William Card (Class of 1915): Postcard from Archibald MacLeish, letter to Mrs. W. W. Card from Andrew Mellon, 1929, 1929, undated (Box 66)
  - No. 252: Bockelman, Charles: "Seven Provosts, Yale, 1969-1987," memoir, 1997 (Box 67)
  - No. 253: Fowler, Joseph (Class of 1834): Notes from lectures, student papers from Yale and Lane Seminary, sermons [three folders], 1828-1837, undated (Box 67)
  - No. 254: Diehl, Sam (Class of 1928): Correspondence, writings, and clippings [correspondence includes description of Diehl's musical performance in the Commons], 1925, 1977 (Box 67)
  - No. 255: Huntington, Joshua H. (Class of 1832, M.D. 1838): "Fractures of the Os Femoris, their variety and treatment,", undated (Box 67)
  - No. 256: Abernethy, John J. (Class of 1825, M.D. 1828): "Theme-Fractures of the Femur,", 1843 (Box 67)
  - No. 257: Amis, Donald (Class of 1910, deceased 1908): Correspondence to family, resolutions of condolence from the Class of 1910 to Amis's parents, 1908-1910 (Box 67)
  - No. 258: Martin, Newell (Class of 1875): Typescript of letters to the New York Times protesting the objection of Yale authorities to wine at the dinner for the fiftieth reunion of the Class of 1875, 1925 (Box 67)
  - No. 259: Hart, Larry (Class of 1936): Correspondence to and about Bartlett A. Giamatti, 1989, 1991 (Box 67)
  - No. 260: Van Sinderen, Adrian: Correspondence with Yale administrators re the Walt Whitman Collection and the Van Sinderen prizes [transferred from the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection, MS 352], 1940-1963 (Box 67)
  - No. 261: Christie, Cornelius (Class of 1855): Letter, photograph, obituary, math exam, 1853-1908 (Box 67)
  - No. 262: Young, Winfred (Class of 1913): Letter describing festivities of prom weekend, 1912 February 1 (Box 67)
  - No. 263: Strong, William (Class of 1828): Letter from Noah Porter re commemorative statue of Benjamin Silliman, 1881 Mar 13, letter from Timothy Dwight re meeting of Yale graduates, 1887 Jul 15, invitation to inauguration of Timothy Dwight, 1886 Jul 1, printed memorabilia, 1850s (Box 67)
  - No. 264: Lohmann, Carl: Correspondence from Bruce Rogers, book designer, relating in part to their collaboration on The Arms of Yale University and Its Colleges at New Haven, 1949-1950, 1954 (Box 67)
  - No. 265: White, Martin: Letters, 1845 Aug 12, 1846 Oct 14, from Denison Olmsted, letter, 1846 Aug 20, from Frederick Starr, regarding admission to Yale College (Box 67)
  - No. 266: Fuller, Daniel (Class of 1808): Diary containing observations on student life and local history, 1806-1807 (Box 67)
  - No. 267: Woolsey Fund of Yale College: Request by the executive committee to alumni for contributions, includes comparison of "educational expenses and receipts of Yale College for the last forty years,", 1874 June 1 (Box 67)
  - No. 268: MacLellan, George Boardman (Class of 1858): Correspondence with friend, Moses H. Messer, describing life at Yale, 1852 June-1855 April (Box 68)
  - No. 269: Bigelow, Otis M. (Class of 1872): Essay on the Chinese in America, 1869 Oct 2; ticket for the Junior Promenade Concert, 1871 Feb 15; program for two plays presented by Delta Beta Xi, 1871 June 9 (Box 68)
  - No. 270: Topic Magazine: first volume, 2002 summer, on the subject of war [includes contributors with Yale affiliations] (Box 68)
  - No. 271: "A Catalogue of Yale College with an Obituary of Deceased Alumni so far as Ascertained," [This twelve feet long handwritten scroll may be viewed in Manuscripts and Archives Digital Image Database (MADID)], 1702-1801 (Box 69)
  - No. 272: Correspondence between M. D. Gilmore, Stuyvesant Fish, and Chester Nimitz, and two sheets of photographs pertaining to the 1904 crew race between Yale and Navy, 1945, undated (Box 70)
  - No. 273: Letter of Augustus Alvey Adee, Class of 1821, to Adam Leopold Alexander, Class of 1821, describing his visit to New Haven and Yale, 1823 September 11 (Box 70)
  - No: 274: Catlin, Abijah (Class of 1825): ALS to his parents, containing a detailed account of General Lafayette's visit to New Haven and Yale College, 1824 August 22 (Box 70)
  - No. 275: Signed petitions requesting co-education admission policies at Yale University, 1970 (Box 70)
  - No. 276: Photograph (6.5" x 16.5"), group, presumably a Yale class, posed in front of a railway car, Circa 1930 (Box 70)
  - No. 277: "Yale Paper Dolls to color and cut out" [watercolors, artist's name illegible], 1983 (Box 70)
  - No. 278: Yale University Register, World's Fair, St. Louis, 1904 (Box 70)
    See: Series IV
  - No. 279: Mounted prints (5) [purportedly used to decorate the room of Nathaniel Bacon, Yale Class of 1833], Circa 1800s (Box 70)
    See: Series V
  - No. 280: Danforth, Robert Melville: Manuscripts, memorabilia, and printed material concerning Danforth's participation in Yale's Batteries, Circa 1916-1940 (Box 71)
  - No. 281: Perkins, Charles (Class of 1813): Commonplace book, 1812-1822 (Box 71)
  - No. 282: McChain, George (Class of 1846): Commonplace book, 1845 (Box 71)
  - No. 283: Speer, William McMurtrie (Class of 1884): Student papers, fundraising activities, 1884-1919 (Box 71)
  - No. 284: Knap(p), Joshua: Photostat of letter to his parents while at Yale, 1767 July 1 (Box 71)
  - No. 285: Hagar, Stansbury Tiffany (1869-1942; Class 1892, Yale College): Notebooks of personal research on pre-Columbian archeology, 2 volumes, Circa 1890 (Box 72)
  - No. 286: Universidad de la Republica, Montevideo, Uruguay. Resolution concerning the world situation, signed by Rector Santiago Sartori. Addressed to the Rector of Yale University. Spanish with English translation, 1940 June 21 (Box 73)
  - No. 287: Letters from two German prisoners of war at Camp Crosville, Tennessee, concerning regulations allowing prisoners of war to attend lectures at American universities. Addressed to the Rector of Yale University, 1943, August (Box 73)
  - No. 288: Foote, Lyman (Yale M.D. 1916):P Memorabilia including photographs, genealogy, and news clippings documenting the family of Dr. Lyman Foote (Box 73)
  - No. 289: Gibbs, James Burnet (Class of 1843): Letter to his brother Charles, including literate account of Silliman lectures and attendance at Harvard commencement, 1842 October 22 (Box 73)
  - No. 290: Hillis, David; two letters to friend Edwin Brevoort while Hillis is visiting Yale Law School, describes New Haven and commencement and class day activities, 1865 June 1and 30 (Box 73)
  - No. 291: Paddock, Robert (Class of 1837): letters to friend Moses Davis at Harvard University, 1835-1836 (Box 73)
  - No. 292: Redpath, Robert Upjohn, Jr. (Class of 1928): "A compilation of the Writings of Robert Upjohn Redpath, Jr.," by Robert Upjohn Redpath III, 2007 (Box 73)
  - No. 293: Pierce, John (1773-1849): Diary excerpt (photostatic copy) describing the inauguration of Timothy Dwight as president of Yale College, 1795 (Box 73)
  - No. 294: Shumway, Floyd M. (Class of 1939): "Yale Remembers Saybrook," and address delivered at the Fellowship Hall of the Congregational Church in Old Saybrook, Connecticut, 1985 March 26 (Box 73)
  - No. 295: Document containing signatures, addresses, and academic background of six students (three Yale alumni); (item was used in Guy Erwin exhibit on the history of the Graduate School, 1997), circa 1890s (Box 73)
  - No. 296: Diary of a sailing trip on the yawl footpad along the Maine Coast, primarily by two Yale undergraduates, Leslie Soule and Frank F. Randolph (Yale College 1911), 1910 (Box 73)
  - No. 297: Byers, Alexander McBurney (1872-1899): Diary of his travels in Europe following graduation from the Sheffield Scientific School in 1894 (Box 73)
  - No. 298: Creeley, Robert ("Bob") (1926-2005): typed letter signed, to another American Beat poet, Diane di Prima (1934- ). Creeley wrote that he would be at Yale University on March 8 or 9, 1965., 1965 February 13 (Box 73)
  - No. 299: Alfred, Randall, papers, 1973-1990 (Box 73)
    Randy Alfred's papers include correspondence, fliers, clippings, and event programs that document the struggle in 1981 to get the Yale Alumni Magazine's Class Notes to use the word "gay" and to treat communications from all classmates without bias based on sexual orientation. Also documented is the Class of 1967's hosting in 1982 of alumni from all classes for the first official LGBT reunion event.
  - No. 300: Essays written by Lemuel Whitman, Yale College, Class of 1800., 1798-1800 (Box 73)
    Some of the essays were written to be read before the Linonian Society.
  - No. 301: Collected correspondence between Robert Osborn and Robert U. Redpath, Jr., 1948-1971 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - No. 302: "Log book of a thousand mile canoe trip", 1894 June-August (Box 75)
    A volume titled, "Log book of a thousand mile canoe trip", June 27 to August 1894, to Quebec and back to New Haven via steamer, railroad, and canoe. Created by George W. Mixter, 1895S, who participated with fellow Sheffield Scientific School classmates: Harry W. Foote, 1895S; Arthur Brewer, 1894S; Winchester Bennett, 1897S; and Edward S. Uhl, 1894S.
  - No. 303: Baldwin, Henry Ives, photograph album, 1923 (Box 76)
    Henry Baldwin (Yale BS 1919, MF 1922, PhD 1931) studied at the Swedish Forestry School, 1923-1924.
    The album contains photographs of Scandinavian forests and silviculture. The majority are from Sweden, but Denmark and Norway are also represented.
  - No. 304: Scrapbook of George Stanley Dewey, 1858-1885 (Box 77)
  - No. 305: King, Carol, "Two New Haven Loyalists: Abiathar Camp, Sr. and Abiathar Camp, Jr., 1985 (Box 73)
  - No. 306: Law, William Henry, "The Birth of the Yale News", undated (Box 74, Folder 2)
    Photocopy of an annotated typescript of "The Birth of the Yale News," a history of the Yale Daily News.
- Yale Miscellaneous Manuscripts Folios: Alphabetical
  - (A-K)
    - Aetna Insurance Company, 1887 (Box IA)
    - Babb, James T., 1946, 1950, 1961 (Box IA)
    - Bacon, Francis, 1889 (Box IA)
    - Baldwin, Simeon Eben, 1898, 1900, 1912 (Box IA)